Guide to the Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1927-1995; Series VII; 2.46; (5 boxes)
  - Artnews, 1983 (Box 36)
  - Connoisseur, 1985 (Box 36)
  - Sculpture Associates, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated; 2 (Box 36)
  - American Poet, 1941-1943; 4 (Box 37)
  - De Lisio exhibition catalogs, 1970-1998; 3 (Box 37)
  - WPA stories for children by Irving Drutman (The Buried Treasure, The Proud Prince) and other authors (The Table and the Chair, Marco Polo, Princess Flinda, and The Crows and the Doves), 1937; 2 (Box 38)
  - David Levine calendar and portfolio, 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - Poster for De Lisio exhibition at Smith College Museum of Art, 1980 (Box 38)
  - Life Magazine, 1968-1971; 3 (Box 39)
  - Unsorted printed material, undated; 2 (Box 39)
- Artwork, 1938-1965; Series VIII; (2 sculptures, 16 paintings)
  Series IX is organized into three subseries: Michael De Lisio, Irving Drutman, and Other Artists.
  This series contains artwork by De Lisio and Drutman, including two of De Lisio's sculptures and several paintings by Drutman. The series also includes portraits of De Lisio and Drutman by Al Hirschfeld and Larry Rivers.
  - Michael De Lisio
    - Sculpture of Ezra Pound, bronze, undated (Box 40 (Art))
    - Sculpture of Marianne Moore, bronze, undated (Box 41 (Art))
    - Painting of dancer, undated (Box 42 (Art))
    - Painting of a seated, headless man, with two faces on either side, undated (Box 43 (Art))
  - Irving Drutman
    - Painting of people in a bar, 1938 (Box 44 (Art))
    - Painting of buildings, 1942 (Box 45 (Art))
    - Painting of people in an art gallery, 1944 (Box 46 (Art))
    - Painting of people in an art gallery, undated (Box 47 (Art))
    - Painting of theatre stage and performers, 1946 (Box 48 (Art))
    - Painting of a theatre with performers and audience, 1948 (Box 49 (Art))
    - Portrait of unidentified man, possibly self-portrait, 1940 (Box 50 (Art))
    - Portrait of a man reading in a navy uniform, undated (Box 51 (Art))
    - Painting of a man reading a paper, undated (Box 52 (Art))
    - "Purging thick amber...", 1955 (Box 53 (Art))
    - Painting of a man sleeping on a couch, 1969 (Box 54 (Art))
  - Other Artists
    - Hirschfeld, Al, portrait of Irving Drutman, undated (Box 55 (Art))
    - Rivers, Larry, portrait of Michael De Lisio, 1954 (Box 56 (Art))
    - Unidentified, painting of artist at easel, undated (Box 57 (Art))
- Oversize, 1925-1993; 0.08; (1 box)
  - High School diploma -- De Lisio, 1930 (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Elementary School diploma -- De Lisio, 1925 (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Sketchpad and drawing, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Material pertaining to proposed Henry James statue in Washington Square, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - "De Lisio Songs: Poems by Michael De Lisio and Music by Gerald Busby", 1993 (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Laura Newell, photographs, signed by Newell, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Ranne Owens & Irving Drutman, photograph, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Fire Island, photographs, undated; 2 (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Unsorted papers, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Portraits of De Lisio and Drutman, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))
  - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 58 (Oversize))